SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer and consultant with experience in JavaScript and Python based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication and collaboration. As a lifelong learner, I continuously work on growing my technical knowledge. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork guides me in achieving exceptional results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon | Fulfillment Operation Lead/Quality Assurance Specialist May 2021 - present

- Leading the daily management of department duties, including allocating labor, leading meetings and assigning job duties.
- o Tracking and reporting ATS labor hours; maintenance of hours and schedules.
- o Participating and drive safety initiatives; Coach associates to always work safely.
- o Training level1 Leads and providing converge for other department leaders.
- Interacting with property managers as needed to address concerns with service levels being provided.
- o Observing deliveries in the field to identify barriers to first-time delivery success; recommend solutions and improvements to Amazon's systems and processes.

University of Guelph | Graduate Teaching/Research Assistant Jan 2019 - Apr 2021

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students at a time) with variety of instructional approaches and presentation methods including MS powerpoint, blackboard, online tools, etc.
- Evaluated students' performances on regular basis by designing assessment problems and grading their respective written reports, video reports, assignments, exams, and classroom activities.
- o Provided coverage for Professors in lectures.
- Wrote progress reports and presented weekly updates of the progression of projects and outlined plans and suggestions for the upcoming work and improvements.
- Resolved students' problems of marking, attendance, and understanding, and motivated them through recognizing the challenges they face throughout the course.
- o Designed experimental setup for fluid research and published a research paper in the field.

KFUPM | Graduate Teaching/Research Assistant

Sep 2016 - Dec 2018

- Conducted research on liquid loading in gas wells supported by faculty members and Saudi Aramco.
- Authored two scientific journal papers in the areas of fluid mechanics, heat transfer, and thermodynamics.
- o Proctored Major and final exams of various courses within the department on regular basis.

PROJECTS

WriteWell- GitHub | Demo | Live

A full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- o Built with Next.js for the front end and styled with scss.
- $\circ\,$ Employed Next.js routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- o Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- o Used AWS S3 to save all images and linked it to the database.
- o Being in-progress for responsive design.

Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- o Employed Next.js with Tailwindcss to design the app as a single page.
- o Incorporated interactive elements and animation using Framer motion.
- o Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files.

GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Demo | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- o Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Utilized BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling.
- o Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- o Employed python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding.
- o Utilized SQLAlchemy for database management.
- o Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

Mohammad El Prince

Software Engineer

Legal name: Mohamed Hussein

- elprince.net
- +1 (519) 760-1559
- mohammad-elprince@proton.me
- Milton, ON
- linkedin.com/in/mohammad-elprince/
- github.com/elprince-dev/

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript - Python - MatLab

Front-end

HTML - CSS - React.js - Next.js - Sass

Back-end

Flask - FastAPI

Database

SQLite3 - MySQL - PostgreSQL

Source Controls and Tools

Git - GitHub - VSCode - Linux WSL

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Flatiron School Feb 23 – Oct 23

MEng. Mechanical Engineering

University of Guelph GPA: 91% (Course-based) Jan 19 – Feb 21

MSc. Mechanical Engineering

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals GPA: 3.95/4.00 (Thesis-based) Sep 16 – Dec 18

BSc. Mechanical Engineering

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals GPA: 3.92/4.00 Jan 12 – May 16

LANGUAGES

Arabic (Native) English (Professional)

INTERESTS

Chess - Tennis - Table Tennis - Soccer